Finding Aid for James and Sybil Irwin family papers, 1815-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
James and Sybil Irwin family papers 1815-1987, 1832-1946
Irwin family.
(in 8 boxes)
6.3 linear feet
87341 Aa 2
James and Sybil (Hunter) Irwin were early setters of Washtenaw County, Michigan. Their two sons, John E. and (James) Leman Irwin, fought in the Civil War as volunteer members of the 20th Michigan Infantry. Correspondence, diaries, and ledgers from these and other branches of the family are preserved in the Irwin family papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received from the heirs of James and Sybil Irwin (donor no. 7476 ) in August and September 2007.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Irwin family were early settlers of Washtenaw County, Michigan. James Irwin was born in New York in 1810 and removed to Saline, Michigan in 1831. His wife, Sybil Hunter, came to Michigan from New York with her parents in 1832.
James and Sybil (Hunter) Irwin had two sons, John E. and (James) Leman Irwin, who would each enlist as soldiers in the Civil War as volunteers in the 20th Michigan Infantry. (James) Leman Irwin died in combat in the early days of the Siege of Petersburg, 17 June 1864. A daughter, Harriet S. (Hattie) Irwin, became a schoolteacher and lived for some time in Nevada. The veteran John E. Irwin married Amy Rice and lived in Michigan for the remainder of his life. They had two sons: Max H. and Fred C. Irwin. In 1890 and 1891 Max H. and Fred C. Irwin prospected on the Iron Range of Northern Minnesota.
The James and Sybil Irwin family papers feature letters written from various Civil War battlefields and encampments by the brothers John E. and (James) Leman Irwin. There are four additional Civil War letters from cousins Samuel H. Row, James H. Irwin, S. Baker, and S.H. Loveland, as well as a transcription of William B. Irwin's journal. The collection also provides insight into the lives of Michigan farmers in the second half of the 19th Century and early 20th Century by way of letters, ledgers, photographs, and diaries. In addition, the correspondence record details the experience of prospectors on the Minnesota Iron Range and life on a Great Lakes freighter. Also extant are sketches by Harriet (Hattie) Irwin, poetry by Harriet and Civil War veterans John E. Irwin and Samuel H. Row, and some early documents pertaining to the North Sharon Methodist Episcopal Church.
The James and Sybil Irwin family papers are divided into the following series largely as maintained by the donor: Civil War Materials; the Baker-Rice and Irwin Families; the individuals Amy (Rice) Irwin, Fred C. Irwin, Harriet S. Irwin, Isaac Irwin, James and Sybil (Hunter) Irwin, John E. Irwin, Max H. Irwin, (James) Leman Irwin, and Max H. Irwin; the North Sharon Methodist Episcopal Church; Miscellaneous items; and Postcards.
Subjects:
Grass Lake (Mich.); Iron mines and mining--Minnesota.; Minnesota.; Nevada.; North Sharon Methodist Episcopal Church (Sharon, Washtenaw County, Mich.); Sharon (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Sharon Mills (Mich.); Shipping--Great Lakes (North America); Teachers--Nevada.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 20th (1862-1865). Company C.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 20th (1862-1865). Company F.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 26th (1862-1865). Company H.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Grass Lake (Mich.); Irwin family.
Contributors:
Irwin, Fred C.; Irwin, Harriet S.; Irwin, James Leman, 1838-1864.; Irwin, John E., b. 1841.; Irwin, Max H.; Irwin, William Bradford.; White, Maxine Irwin.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Civil War Materials
  The Civil War Materials series contains both the original letters and Maxine (Irwin) White's typed and indexed transcription of the correspondence of brothers John E. and (James) Leman Irwin, who fought in the Civil War as volunteer members of the 20th Michigan Infantry. Also included is an 1864 field journal by John E. Irwin. There is also a typed transcription of the journal of William Bradford Irwin (William B. Irwin of Delhi, Michigan enlisted in Company H, 26th Michigan Infantry, 13 Sept. 1862, at Mason, Michigan. The location of the original diary is not known).The series also contains materials that have not been transcribed, such as correspondence from the front written by relatives James H. Irwin of New York, Company I 1st Veteran Cavalry, S.H. Loveland of the 8th Michigan Infantry, and S. Baker. Also included is a letter from veteran cousin Samuel H. Row to John E. Irwin shortly after the close of the war in 1865, 20th Michigan Infantry ephemera, applications for bounty on behalf of deceased sons filed by James Irwin and Orrin Row, and an 1864 ledger kept by John E. Irwin.
  - Typed Transcriptions
    (microfilm copy available)
    - Typed transcription of the Civil War Letters of John E. Irwin, (James) Leman Irwin, and their family, compiled by Maxine Irwin White (Box 1)
    - Typed Transcription of the Journal of William Bradford Irwin 1862-1865 (Box 1)
  - Originals
    (transcript copies available)
    - Aunt Olive to nephew John E. Irwin 1863 (Box 1)
    - Harriet Irwin to brothers John E. and (James) Leman (Box 1)
      (incl. one sketch)
    - (James) Leman Irwin Tribute (Box 1)
    - (James) Leman Irwin to sisters Harriet and parents 1862-1864 (Box 1)
    - John E. Irwin Letters 1862 (Box 1)
    - John E. Irwin Letters 1863 (Box 1)
      (1 letter in oversize box 7)
    - John E. Irwin Letters 1864, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - John E. Irwin Field Diary 1864 (Box 1)
    - John E. Irwin Letters 1865 (Box 1)
    - Sybil Irwin, also James and Harriet, to son John E. Irwin 1863-1865 (Box 1)
    - Samuel H. Row Obituary 1905 (Box 1)
  - Originals
    (no transcript copies available)
    - 20th Michigan Infantry Ephemera (Box 1)
      (incl. hospital and clothing reports, transportation notice, inspection letter, and untitled lists)
    - Correspondence
      - S. Baker to "Wife & Children," March 19, 1865 (Box 1)
      - James H. Irwin of New York, Company I 1st Veteran Cavalry, to Uncle and Aunt James and Sybil Irwin from Camp Stoneman, New York November 15, 1863 (Box 1)
      - S.H. Loveland, 8th Michigan Infantry to "Brother & Sister," March 26, 1865 from near Petersburg, Virginia (Box 1)
      - Samuel H. Row to cousin John E. Irwin 1865 (Box 1)
    - James Irwin and Orrin Row Applications for Bounty on Behalf of Deceased Sons 1864-1866 (Box 1)
    - John E. Irwin Ledger 1864 (Box 1)
    - John E. Irwin Civil War Military Promotion Certificates 1862, 1863, 1865 (Box 7)
      (in Box 7, folder 2)
    - Morning Reports of Capt. H.R. Carpenter, Company B, 20th Regiment of Michigan Infantry May 1865 (Box 7)
    - "Papers Almost Priceless Relating To Army Life" (Box 1)
      (Furlough, Discharge, and Pension of John E. Irwin)
- Baker-Rice Family
  A small collection of papers from the Baker-Rice families are preserved in this collection, as Amy (Rice) Irwin was the daughter of John W. and Mary (Baker) Rice.
  - Hoziel H. Baker Teaching and Discharge Certificates 1815, 1818 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    (incl. C. C. Stevenson, Lewis E. Rice of San Francisco, H.H. Baker of New York, Francis M. Baker, Eleanor and Sarah Baker of Stockbridge, Mich., John M. Rice, Lorenzo Baker, Elizabeth R. Baker of New York, Laura Emelina Rice of Stockbridge, and Calista and Nancy Rice of Stockbridge)
  - Elizabeth Rice Probate 1916-1927 (Box 1)
  - Mary (Baker) Rice Ephemera (Box 1)
    (incl. obituary)
- Irwin Family
  The Irwin Family series includes three photo albums, a collection of deeds, and other realia.
  - Deeds, Mortgages, and Fire Insurance 1852-1937 (Box 8)
  - Deeds 1853-1937 (Box 7)
    (in Box 7, Oversize Folder 2)
  - Invitations and Programs 1862-1912 (Box 8)
  - Photo Albums
    - "At Irwin Farm," 1908-1920 (Box 8)
      (also pictured are Dr. Horace Colgan, Florence Sherwood, Koebbe's Sawmill, Roena Waltrous, and Keith Hewes)
    - "At Irwin Farm" Loose Items (Box 8)
    - "Father's Pictures Volume IV," circa 1920-1949 (Box 8)
      (also pictured are Clarence Baker, Gertrude Nash, Lester Nash, J.R. Lemm, and a 12" Railway Mount)
    - "Father's Pictures Volume IV" Loose Items (Box 8)
    - Portrait Album (Box 8)
  - Receipts 1842-1862 (Box 2)
  - Wedding Invitations 1872-1926 (Box 2)
- Amy (Rice) Irwin
  Amy (Rice) Irwin was born in Stockbridge, Michigan on 30 June 1848, the daughter of John W. and Mary (Baker) Rice and daughter-in-law of James and Sybil Irwin. She married John E. Irwin in 1869 and died 21 September 1927, surviving her husband by eight years. Throughout her life she maintained a correspondence network with many members of her family.
  - Address Change (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - 1915-1927 (mostly outgoing to son Fred) (Box 2)
    - Incoming and Outgoing (mostly to children) 1894 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Dell, Bertha, and Clarence Baker 1919-1927 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Louis and Mary Baker DeLamarter 1880-1927 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Mary and Helen Gillett 1918-1929 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from William J. Girvin 1923-1926 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Fannie Holden, Mary Stow, Olive Cadwell, Myrtilla Davis, Virginia McFadden, Cara W. Kroonz, Gertrude Howe, Elizabeth Raymond, Wilda V. Brown, Ida Coover, and others (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Florette E. (Rice) Hull, Clinton Rice, and William B. Rice 1892-1908 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Hermoine Irving of Duckwater, Nevada 1925-1927 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Clara Ling, Marshall Steinhoff, and Elizabeth Manchester 1892-1919 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Margarite, Ola, and A. Loveland, Ella and Frank Jencks 1912-1919 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Louise Nichols, Irene Hume, Lillian Lathrop, and Lawrence E. Davis 1904-1927 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Lucy A. and Marna Osband (Box 2)
      (some letters written on Republican State Central Committee of Michigan letterhead)
    - Incoming from White House, signed by C. Bascom Slemp, Secretary to the President 1924 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Elizabeth Williams 1907-1926 (Box 2)
      (incl. poetry)
    - "Grandchildren's Letters to Grandma" (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1921-1927 (Box 2)
  - Ledger Book 1902-1911 (Box 2)
    (incl. recipes)
  - Memo Book (Box 2)
  - Miscellany (Box 2)
  - Power of Attorney 1927 (Box 2)
- Fred C. Irwin
  Fred C. Irwin was born about 1870, the son of John E. and Amy (Rice) Irwin, and grandson of James and Sybil Irwin. He graduated from Grass Lake High School in June 1889, prospected in Northern Minnesota in 1890 and 1891, and attended Annapolis Naval Academy.
  - Annapolis Naval Academy Appointment, Speeches, Compositions, and other Ephemera (Box 2)
  - Contract for Rural Line Extension 1938 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming and Outgoing with Family and Others 1911-1918 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Children 1911-1927 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Maude Clement Irwin of Rochester, New York, some addressed to Fred's son Charles 1912-1923 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Addis Lesson and Mary E. Brockway 1890 (Box 2)
    - Incoming from Marna Osband 1928 (Box 2)
    - Outgoing to brother Max, father John E., and grandfather 1881-1883 (Box 2)
    - Outgoing to Family (mostly parents) 1917-1927 (Box 2)
  - "Crossing the Rubicon," 1889 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript, "Prospecting in Northern Minnesota," 1892 (Box 2)
  - School Ephemera
    - Composition Book 1869 (Box 3)
    - German Composition Book 1893-1894 (Box 3)
    - Grass Lake High School Credits and Adrian College Scholarship 1888-1889 (Box 3)
    - Penmanship (Box 3)
    - Teacher's Certificates and Correspondence from Students 1889-1933 (Box 3)
- Fred C. and Max H. Irwin
  Some letters of Fred C. and Max H. Irwin were filed together, and this series reflects the original order. In 1890 and 1891 the brothers prospected on the Iron Range of Northern Minnesota and a large set of correspondence with their parents details this experience.
  - Correspondence
    - 1895-1903 (Box 3)
    - Ann Arbor 1891-1894 (Box 3)
    - Incoming from J. E. Longyear re: Minnesota (Box 3)
    - Re: Prospecting in Mesaba, Minnesota 1890 (Box 3)
    - Re: Prospecting in Mesaba, Minnesota 1891 (Box 3)
- Harriet S. Irwin
  Harriet S. Irwin, also known as Hattie, was the daughter of James and Sybil Irwin, born about 1845. She lived in Michigan as well as Duckwater and Eureka, Nevada, frontier "boom towns" about 200 and 260 miles north of Las Vegas, working as a schoolteacher for the families of miners and prospectors. Preserved within this series are her correspondence, diaries, poetry, and some sketches.
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming from Lucy Maria (Carpenter) Jones and Miriam/ May (Carpenter) Harris 1865-1868 (Box 3)
    - Incoming from cousin Eliza Nixon 1863 (Box 3)
    - Incoming, Misc. 1909-1910 (Box 3)
      (incl. Edwin E. Row and Alice Stundon)
    - "Hattie in Nevada," Outgoing to Brother John E. Irwin 1891-1920 (Box 3)
      (2 folders)
  - Diary (Box 3)
    (incl. sketches and poetry)
  - Diary (Box 3)
  - Ephemera (Box 3)
    (recommendation letter, 1894; teaching certificates, 1895, 1902; and Independent Order of Oddfellows membership card, 1907)
  - Estate Account Books, Probate Appointments 1920 (Box 3)
  - Eulogies (Box 3)
  - Leather Postcard (Box 3)
    (contains sketches)
  - "Poetry -- Essays & Speeches" (Box 3)
  - Photograph, Mounted Card Photo (Box 3)
  - Receipts, Bank Statements, etc. (Box 3)
  - Receipts (mostly Sharon Township taxes) 1881-1919 (Box 3)
  - Will, Estate Tax Valuation (Box 7)
    (Box 7, folder 1)
- Isaac Irwin
  Isaac Irwin was the brother of James Irwin and the uncle of Harriet (Hattie) Irwin. Like his niece, Isaac lived in Duckwater and Eureka, Nevada. He also lived in Cape Cod, Massachusetts.
  - Correspondence, Incoming from Elizabeth Ferguson (Box 3)
  - Portrait, Mounted Card Photograph (Box 3)
- James and Sybil (Hunter) Irwin
  James and Sybil (Hunter) Irwin were very early settlers in Washtenaw County, Michigan. James Irwin was born in New York in 1810, the son of John Irwin, and removed to Saline, Michigan in 1831. Many of his siblings remained in New York, and a collection of correspondence from the 1830's and 1840's remains. He married Sybil Hunter in 1836, the daughter of Nathaniel and Rhoda (Peck) Hunter. She came to Michigan from New York with her parents in 1832. The Irwins would live in Freedom Township, Sharon Township, and Grass Lake, Michigan. James and Sybil Irwin had two sons, John E. and (James) Leman Irwin, who fought in the Civil War ((James) Leman Irwin died in combat), and a daughter, Harriet S. (Hattie) Irwin, became a schoolteacher and lived for some time in Duckwater and Eureka, Nevada.
  - Account Book 1835-1864 (Box 4)
  - Contracts 1840, 1865 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming 1854-1869 (Box 4)
      (incl. Elizabeth Dickinson, Row family, Miriam (Carpenter) Harris, and others)
    - Incoming from Benjamin and Maria (Irwin) Carpenter 1846-1854 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from cousin Miriam Bennett, brother Isaac Irwin in Cape Cod, and Uncle John Peck in Ohio 1848-1856 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from M. Carpenter (Box 7)
      (Box 7, folder 2)
    - Incoming from father John E. Irwin and siblings Thomas, Clarissa, John, Rachel Darby, and Wardell Yager in New York 1837-1864 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from Wait Peck of New York 1834 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from sisters Harriet Row of Michigan, Catherine, Bulia Williams of New York, and Maria Shook 1832-1838 (Box 4)
  - Endorsement of Bill 1848 (Box 4)
  - Maple Hill Cemetery Association of Grass Lake, Receipt 1888 (Box 4)
- John E. Irwin
  John E. Irwin was born 9 May 1841 in Freedom Township, the son of James and Sybil Irwin, and attended the Normal School in Ypsilanti. He enlisted 20 July 1862 in Company B, Twentieth Michigan Infantry. This company would fight with Morgan's Guerillas and Horseshoe Bend, participated in the sieges of Vicksburg and Knoxville, march with the Army of the Potomac as it advanced toward Richmond, and served under General Grant during the Battle of the Wilderness and Battle of Spotsylvania Court House. John E. Irwin was wounded during the Siege of Petersburg (his brother, (James) Leman, died during this battle) but continued fighting and achieved the rank of Second Lieutenant before being discharged on 1 June 1865. He married Amy Rice in Michigan in 1869 and they had two sons: Max H. and Fred C. Irwin. Like his parents, he was a member of the Methodist Episcopal Church and was a prohibitionist. John E. Irwin was also an active member of the Grand Army of the Republic, Post No. 228. He died about 1919. Items in the John E. Irwin series span the length of his life - from an elementary school reader to letters written from his travels with the G.A.R. later in life. An exchange of correspondence with his cousin, Samuel H. Row, also a Civil War veteran, contains epic poetry about their Civil War experiences.
  - Account Book 1873-1906 (Box 7)
    (incl. poetry; in Box 7, Oversize Folder 4)
  - Biography 1891 (Box 4)
  - Civil War Pension and Biographical Notes (Box 4)
  - Confederate Dollar, North Carolina (Box 4)
    (inscribed on back)
  - Correspondence
    - 1890-1908 Outgoing to Cousin Samuel H. Row (Box 4)
      (incl. autobiographical poetry about Civil War experiences, one newspaper clipping)
    - Incoming 1867-1868 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from Frank L. Carpenter 1911 (Box 7)
      (in Box 7, folder 1)
    - Incoming from Cousins in Hunnewell, Missouri (Box 4)
    - Incoming from G.A.R. Comrades 1907-1920 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from Miriam (Carpenter) Harris 1861-1862, 1874 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from Miriam (Carpenter) Harris, Mary E. Harris, Ivy Harris, and John C. Carpenter 1854-1880 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from Claudius B. Grant, Chief Justice, Supreme Court of Michigan 1899-1905 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from William McKinley, prior to election as 25th President of the United States March 31, 1896 (Box 4)
      (photocopy of original)
    - Incoming from Virgil R. and Tina Peck (Box 4)
    - Incoming from Cousin Myron Row 1861 (Box 4)
    - Incoming from A.E. Whale, R.E. Manning, Oscar Loveland, and other 1861-1868 (Box 4)
    - Outgoing from Boston, Mass. and St. Louis, Miss. 1904 (Box 4)
    - Outgoing from G.A.R. Convention 1892 (Box 4)
    - Outgoing from the G.A.R. National Encampment 1902 (Box 4)
    - Outgoing from Lakeside Les Cheneaux (Box 4)
    - Outgoing to Samuel H. Row undated (Box 4)
    - Outgoing to wife and children 1871-1876 (Box 4)
    - Regarding Overdue Contract 1898 (Box 4)
  - Diaries
    - Pre-Civil War (Box 4)
    - 1861, 1865, 1870-1888 (Box 4)
    - 1910-1919, 9 volumes (in 5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Ephemera, Bill Horn's Male Chorus Pocket Edition 1893 (Box 4)
  - Fire Insurance 1882-1919 (Box 4)
    (mostly Washtenaw Mutual Fire Insurance Company)
  - G.A.R. and 20th Michigan Volunteer Infantry Reunion Ephemera (Box 4)
  - G.A.R. Certificate 1889 (Box 7)
    (in Box 7, Oversize Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts
    - "Retrospective Account of Army Life Upon Induction to First Assignment" (Box 4)
      (pages 1 and 2 are missing)
    - Historic Table, Sovereigns of England (Box 7)
  - Poetry Submissions, The American Magazine 1906 (Box 5)
  - Photographs
    - Civil War Reunion Photo, possibly the 20th Michigan Infantry September 1893 (Box 7)
      (about 50 veterans pictured; in Box 7, Oversize Folder 3)
    - Portrait (Box 5)
  - Program, The 49th Annual Dinner of the Survivors of the 20th Michigan Infantry Volunteers, Ann Arbor 1914 (Box 5)
    (incl. photograph)
  - School Ephemera, "The Second Reader, Model Series" (Box 5)
  - Solicitations 1892-1925 (Box 5)
  - Speeches 1906-1907 (Box 5)
  - Tax Receipts, Sharon Township 1869-1911 (Box 5)
  - Teaching Certificates, Contracts, and Notes 1859-1865 (Box 5)
  - Will and Probate 1919 (Box 5)
- (James) Leman Irwin
  (James) Leman Irwin, son of James and Sybil Irwin, enlisted in company F, 20th Michigan Infantry, as a fifer 6 Aug. 1862 and was killed in action during the first days of the Siege at Petersburg, 18 June 1864. This series includes some pre-Civil War correspondence (his Civil War letters are in the Civil War Materials series).
  - Correspondence
    - Outgoing to Brother John E. 1858, 1860 (Box 5)
    - Outgoing to Cousin Samuel H. Row 1861 (Box 5)
- Max H. Irwin
  Max H. Irwin was born 15 November 1873, the son of John E. and Amy (Rice) Irwin, and grandson of James and Sybil Irwin. He prospected in Northern Minnesota in 1890 and 1891 and worked on the Great Lakes in 1903.
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming 1899-1944 (Box 5)
      (incl. WWII Air Mail letter)
    - Incoming and Outgoing with Parents 1889 (Box 5)
    - Incoming from Clarence and Dell Baker 1926, 1940-1949 (Box 5)
    - Incoming from Children 1927-1944 (Box 5)
    - Incoming from Louis and Mary Baker DeLamarter 1909-1931 (Box 5)
    - Incoming from Hermoine and Imogene Irving of Duckwater, Nevada 1928-1947 (Box 5)
      (incl. photographs, poetry)
    - Incoming from Marna Osband 1942-1946 (Box 5)
      (incl. Circuit Court Judge James R. Breakey Jr. election flyer)
    - Incoming, mostly from nephew Charles Irwin 1903-1945 (Box 5)
    - "Max on the Great Lakes," 1903 (Box 5)
    - Outgoing (with some incoming) to Brother Fred and Mother Amy 1911-1943 (Box 5)
  - Picture Postcard (Box 5)
    (portrait of Max H. Irwin)
  - Receipts and Ephemera 1897-1926 (Box 5)
  - Register of Children's Births (Box 5)
  - School Ephemera
    - "1891 Compositions" (Box 5)
      (incl. paper supporting women's suffrage)
    - "Book Peddling Tour" and Other Items (Box 5)
- North Sharon Methodist Episcopal Church
  James Irwin was involved in the formation of the North Sharon Methodist Episcopal Church and helped organize their Sunday School program. These records and others are extant in this series.
  - Class Book 1884-1892 (Box 5)
  - Finances 1894-1914 (Box 5)
  - First Meeting of the Trustees 1848 (Box 5)
  - "North Sharon School and Church Notes" (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series includes items from the Irwin collection which were not directly related to the immediate family of James and Sybil (Hunter) Irwin, including correspondence from the Berry and Carpenter families and a set of early Washtenaw County deeds. Also included is a ledger book from Sharon Mills (proprietors Rice and Champlin), dated 1856-1867, an account book dated 1831-1832, and an assortment of loose photographs, poetry, and recipes.
  - 17th Michigan Infantry, Stonewall Regiment, Roster 1892 Reunion (Box 5)
  - Account Book 1831-1832 (Box 5)
  - Calling Cards (Box 5)
  - Correspondence
    - "Aunt Maria" (poss. Carpenter) to Augustus 1869 (Box 5)
    - Clarissa (Irwin) Berry to S. Irwin 1851 (Box 5)
    - From Lucy Maria (Carpenter) Jones to John E. and Amy (Rice) Irwin and Harriet Irwin 1862-1922 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Deeds, Miscellaneous (Many Pertaining to Samuel H. Smith), Washtenaw County 1861-1892 (Box 5)
  - Deeds, Miscellaneous, Washtenaw County 1852-1891 (Box 7)
  - Genealogy -- Names and Addresses (Box 5)
  - Donald Irwin
    - Birth Certificate (copy) 1912 (Box 5)
    - Contracts, Receipts, Ration Coupons, and other Ephemera 1936-1951 (Box 5)
    - Irwin School, District No. 8, Sharon Township, Washtenaw County, Souvenir 1921 (Box 5)
  - Charles Irwin School Papers 1917 (Box 5)
  - "Notes and Sketches" (Box 5)
  - Photographs
    - Bertie Cresswell (Box 5)
    - G.A.R. National Encampment Mounted Card Photos (Box 7)
    - Veryl Irwin at Granddaughter's Wedding August 1987 (Box 5)
    - Loose Mounted Card Photos (Box 5)
    - Edward Stearns' Home in Florida (Box 5)
    - Unidentified (Box 5)
  - Poetry (Box 5)
  - Program, 20th Annual Meeting of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union of Michigan, Ann Arbor 1894 (Box 5)